

## Mir Faisal Ahmad

Front-end web Developer

As a web designer, I bring creativity, technical expertise and a passion for design to every project. I have the skills to turn a client's vision into a visually stunning and user-friendly website that engages and informs visitors. I am a master of design and a problem-solver, who stays up-to-date on the latest design trends and technologies. Let me help you create a website that stands out and showcases your brand in the best light possible. Let's work together and make it happen.

mirfaisal08@gmail.com

P Dhaka, Bangladesh

in linkedin.com/in/mirfaisal08

instagram.com/7ven9en3ee

### 01729-321092

mirfaisal.github.io/mir-faisal-portfolio/

github.com/MirFaisal

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Web Design Intern Creative IT Institute

08/2022 - 01/2023

Dhaka, Bangladesh
Creative IT Institute is a trusted organization dedicated to creating breakthroughs
in IT. Since its inception, Creative IT has been contributing to building Digital
Bangladesh for a long 14 years and achieving multi-faceted success through
groundbreaking changes. Since 2008, this IT company, one of the most important
in Banaladesh

#### Tasks

- Build a landing page for BrightSkills App.
- Build a responsive website with a bunch of different CSS frameworks.

# **Tuition as web design**Online - Google Meet | Zoom

01/2019 - Present

Home tuition for me as a web designer is a great way to teach students online, allowing them to learn at their own pace in their own homes. I can provide individualized instruction on various web design topics such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and more. I can also allow students to work on real-world projects and help them develop the skills they need to succeed in the web design industry. With online home tuition, students have flexibility in their schedule and can learn at their convenience. Overall, home tuition is a valuable option for anyone looking to improve their web design skills and take their career to the next level.

### **EDUCATION**

## Responsive web design

Creative IT Institute

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Courses

- Web Design
- Soft Skills

### **Diploma in engineering** Rajshahi Polytechnic Institute

01/2018 - 01/2023

Rajshahi, Bangladesh

Мајог

- Computer Technology

## Secondary School Certificate (SSC)

Naogaon Zilla School

Naogaon, Bangladesh

Мајог

- Science

### **SKILLS**



### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

The web contest organized by Creative IT institute (12/2022)

Show

Champion

### VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Red cross youth volunteer (06/2017 - Present)

 In 2017 I was the team leader in my local area for grameenphone to provide 1 Crore Taka relief to the flood victims

Animal Rescuer at local area (01/2019 - Present)

 An experienced animal rescuer with a passion for helping stray and abandoned animals. Skilled in first aid, fostering and socializing animals, and working with a team. Proficient in animal behavior and handling, and knowledgeable of animal laws

### **CERTIFICATES**

Human-Centered Design (01/2023 - Present)

Master human-centered design with IDEO.org to solve real world challenges

Adaptive Leadership in Development (01/2023 - Present)

This course forms part of the Leadership in Global Development MicroMasters® Program offered by The University of Queensland (UQ). Completing all four classes and obtaining a verified certificate in all of these means that you have completed the Micro Masters program (unless you have completed a course in the LGDMx series before 2020).

### **ORGANIZATIONS**

Bangladesh Red Crescent Society (03/2017 - Present)
Youth and Volunteers

### **LANGUAGES**

English

Professional Working Proficiency

### **INTERESTS**

Gardening

**BR** Gaming

Traveling